so let's look at the solution of our
msync quiz
this processor allows all possible
reorderings however
it only allows reorderings of accesses
to different locations
because cache coherence and correct
uniprocessor behavior ensures that
accesses to the same variable
are still done in correct order
so we don't have to worry about
the ll and sc and the store being
reordered with respect to each other
they're still going to behave
exactly as if they were in program order
however
the variable and the lock are different
memory locations so they can be
arbitrarily reordered here
so what can happen is that this load of
a variable
could be moved all the way up
before we even try to acquire the lock
so now we are loading potentially while
somebody is still in their critical
section so what we need is an msync here
to ensure that we first get the lock
and only then try to actually do our
work in the critical section so that our
work doesn't escape the critical section
now another problem is that stores in
this browser can be reordered so we can
easily
release the lock
and then update the variable which again
we need to prevent
so we need to prevent that type of
reordering we don't have to put an msync
here because the load of the variable
and the store will happen in order
because they're to the same memory
location and we don't have to put
anything here or anywhere in between
because
the all of these accesses to the lock
are going to be in program order anyway
in general a lock function
is considered to be an acquired type of
synchronization and then we put an msync
after it and unlock is considered to be
a release type of synchronization and we
put an m sync before it so the idea is
that you first acquire access to
something then um sync then you actually
access it to make sure that you access
it after you acquire it and then when
you want to release
you first do what you want then msync
then release to make sure that the
release actually happens after the work
is done
with flag synchronization we have seen
that waiting for a flag is an acquire
and that releasing the flag is really a
release and then a barrier is a weird
case where we have both an acquire and
the release in the same operation
so we need an m sync both before and
after the barrier to ensure that the
work gets done before we enter the
barrier
and that nobody leaves
until we are done with the barrier